怎么样啊今天...
So, tell me about your day... how's it going
粒子探测器弄得如何?
with the particle detector?
哇! 你还记得呐?
Wow! You remember that?
当然 我懂得倾听
Yeah, I listen to what you say.
你在用超流体氦
You're building a particle detector
搭建一个粒子探测器
using superfluid helium.
当你这么说话时
You know, when you talk like that,
真想把你扑倒在这桌子上
I want to take you right here on this table.
以历史经验来看
And you know from past experience
这桌子承受不了我们俩的重量
this table cannot support both our weight.
探测器到底怎么样啊?
So, how's the detector going?
超流体还是很难对付的
Well, it's tricky working with superfluids.
不论你把它们放进什么容器
Whatever container you put them in,
他们都会自己
they kind of creep up the sides
沿着侧壁爬出来
and crawl out all on their own.
有点像Sheldon的蚂蚁农场
Kind of like Sheldon's ant farm.
精辟 但是你不会见到一个疯子边跑
Exactly, except you don't have a lunatic running around,
边嚎叫"我喂你糖水 你为什么咬我?"
yelling, "I fed you sugar water, why are you biting me?"
这好无聊... 你真想聊这个?
Come on, this is boring... you really want to talk about this?
当然了
No, I do.
这餐巾纸上的"超流体氦"
I... I didn't write "superfluid helium"
可不是白写的
on this napkin for nothing.
那好吧...
Okay, well...
还是挺酷的
This is cool.
有一个"超流体真空理论"
Uh, there's a thing called "superfluid vacuum theory",
真空区被想象成一个带着所有
where empty space is imagined as a superfluid
特性的超流体...
with all of its qualities...
粘度 密度 表面张力...
viscosity, density, surface tension...
如果你为了戏剧性效果而暂停
Hey, if you're pausing for dramatic effect,
那请继续
I'd keep it moving.
不 不
No, no.
一般不讨论表面张力
People don't talk about surface tension.
如果把我们的三维空间想象成
If you imagine our three-space as the surface
一个N维超流体气泡的表面...
of an N-dimensional superfluid bubble...
这... 太激动人心了
This... is exciting.
真是太激动人心了
This is really exciting.
我得去找Sheldon
I have to go find Sheldon.
好吧 如果你找到他
Okay, well, if you find him,
记得扑倒在厨房结实的中岛上...
use the kitchen island...
咖啡桌可受不了你们两个
that coffee table will not support both of you.
就是说一个球形的多维度超流体
Which means a spherical multidimensional superfluid
具有和时空同样的反向能量密度
shows the same negative-energy density as space-time.
你怎么看? 怎么看? 你怎么看?
So what do you think? What do you think? So what do you think?
嗯...
Hmm...
怎么? 错了吗?
What? Is it wrong?
你在别的地方见过?
Have you seen it somewhere else?
嗯...
Hmm...
我知道这不属于我的研究领域
I know this isn't my area,
我数学也没你好
and I could never do the math like you can,
但这想法是不是有戏...?
but could this be something...?
好吧...
Well...
把牛顿的引力常量设成1比较好
You could have set Newton's gravitational constant to one.
而且 这些字有股蓝莓的恶臭
And, ugh, the whole thing reeks of blueberry.
我最受不了带味道的马克笔了 这你是知道的
You know I can't stand these scented markers.
没人让你去舔啊
No one told you to taste them.
拜托 这... 这个到底对不对啊?
Come on, is... is this good or not?
对
It's good.
- 真的?  - 我喜欢
- Really?  - I like it.
你有戏
I think you're on to something.
你真这么想? 不是骗我吧?
You do? You're not messing with me?
当然不
Not at all.
事实上 我为此情此景专门
In fact, I have got something
给你准备了个礼物
for just such an occasion.
我原来以为
I was starting to think
永远不会有机会送给你了呢
I might never get a chance to give it to you.
点个赞
Good job.
给我一张贴纸?
You're giving me a sticker?
不是一般的贴纸
Not just a sticker.
是一张有猫猫"喵噻!"的贴纸
That is a sticker of a kitty saying, "Me-wow!"
我又不是三岁小孩
I'm not a preschooler.
那好吧 我收回
Fine, I'll take it back.
这是我赚来的! 别过来!
I earned this! Back off!
* 宇宙一度又烫又稠密 *
* Our whole universe was in a hot, dense state *
* 140亿年前终于爆了炸... 等着瞧! *
* Then nearly 14 billion years ago expansion started... Wait! *
* 地球开始降温 *
* The Earth began to cool *
* 自养生物来起哄 穴居人发明工具 *
* The autotrophs began to drool, Neanderthals developed tools *
* 我们建长城 我们建金字塔 *
* We built the Wall We built the pyramids *
* 数学 自然科学 历史 揭开神秘 *
* Math, Science, History, unraveling the mystery *
* 一切由大爆炸开始 *
* That all started with a big bang *
生活大爆炸 第八季十四集
--==圣城家园SCG字幕组 http://hdscg.com/==--
仅供翻译交流使用, 禁止用于商业用途
协调: 没吃完火锅的心痛酥
翻译: 眉毛兔 猫呗 奥利奥
校对: UU养了只狐狸叫查理
还没睡?
You're still awake?
对于一个刚刚发现了
For a man whose last observation was
我们的宇宙可能是
our universe may be the surface
多维度超冷液体的表面的男人来说
of a multidimensional supercooled liquid,
"还没睡"是不是有点太"大二症"了
"you're still awake" seems like quite the sophomore slump.
通常指高二或大二学生心情低迷的症状
你把公式都列出来了
You worked out all the math.
可不止公式
Oh, I did more than work out all the math.
我写了篇论文
I wrote a paper.
你用我的想法写论文?
You wrote a paper on my idea?
我用我们的想法写论文
I wrote a paper on our idea.
什么时候我的想法变成了我们的想法?
When did my idea become our idea?
当我加入Sheldon佐料
When I mixed it with Sheldony goodness
在我脑中的迷你烤炉中烘烤过之后
and cooked it in the Easy-Bake Oven of my mind.
真妙啊
This is good.
我们的想法太妙了
Our idea is really good.
烤炉里的灯泡可是超级亮啊
Well, the lightbulb in this oven is ridiculously bright.
bright也可译为聪明
如果没有其他人想到
You know, if no one's thought of this, yet,
这可是件大事啊
this could be a big deal.
只有上传到预发表服务器
Only way we'll know for sure is
才能确定啊
if we post it online to the pre-print server.
我准备好了 但是你不来我不会发的
I have it ready to go, but I wasn't gonna do it without you.
哇 这一切来的太突然了
Wow, it's all happening so fast.
我们是不是先睡一觉冷静一下?
Should we just sleep on it?
可以啊 但是我们要冒着
We could, but we always run the risk
被人抢先的风险
of someone else beating us to the punch.
你确定没问题吗?
You're sure it's good?
我的名字也在上面
My name is right on there with yours.
这就是质量的保证
That is a surefire mark of quality.
就像是说"由Joss Whedon导演"
That might as well say "Directed by Joss Whedon".
(曾执导复仇者联盟 神盾局)
好 哥们 来吧
Okay, partner, let's do it.
来
Come on.
同我一起点击鼠标
Click the mouse with me.
一...
One...
二...
two...
三...
three...
点
Click.
我们搞定了
Well, we did it.
是啊 我的朋友
Yes, we did, my friend.
你舌头是蓝的?
Is your tongue blue?
我不想聊这事
I don't want to talk about it.
电影之夜... 你们想看什么?
Okay, movie night... what do you want to watch?
你演的那个猩猩电影到底怎么了?
What happened to that ape movie you were in?
噢上帝
Oh, God.
可能是白干了
Probably nothing.
我好像在Verizon店门口看到
I think I saw the director twirling a sign
导演耍牌子拉顾客来着
outside the Verizon store.
快搜
Search for it.
什么... 别啊
Wha... no.
别! 为什么?
No! Why?
因为肯定很搞笑啊
'Cause it would be fun to watch.
太丢脸了
It would be humiliating.
那现在有两个理由看了
Well, now we have two reasons.
真的有
They have it.
拜托 我们可以看吗?
Please, can we watch it?
求求你啦?
Please?
好吧 但是我告诉你们... 很糟糕
Fine, but I'm telling you... it's terrible.
- 你看过吗?  - 没
- Have you even seen it?  - No.
那可能比你想象的要好
Well, maybe it turned out better than you think.
香蕉 新鲜的香蕉
Bananas, get your fresh bananas.
果然很糟
It really didn't.
Sheldon 这就是超流体氦
Sheldon, this is superfluid helium.
放进嘴里
Put this in your mouth,
会把你舌头冻掉
your tongue will freeze and break off.
有蓝莓味吗?
Does it smell like blueberries?
没有
No.
那就没事
Then we're probably okay.
量子日记的博客提到了
Hey, your paper got mentioned
你们的论文
on the Quantum Diaries physics blog.
真的吗?
Really?
上面怎么说的?
Wh... What'd they say?
只是概括了一下理论
Uh, it's basically a summary of the theory,
但是留言板上有很多正面评价
but there's a bunch of positive comments on the message board.
让我看看 让我看看
Let me see, let me see.
有人评价"有见地 有创意"
One calls it "insightful and innovative".
我们有见地有创意
We're insightful and innovative.
很高兴见到你 有见地先生
Ooh, nice to meet you, Mr. Insightful.
我也是 有创意先生
Oh, the pleasure is mine, Mr. Innovative.
啊 还有说 "这个观点表现出
Uh, another one says, "The concept shows
一些不拘泥于传统的思维"
some real out-of-the-box thinking".
你听到了吗 不拘泥先生?
Do you hear that, Mr. Out-Of-The?
听到了 传统思维先生
I do, indeed, Mr. Box-Thinking.
你好吗
How are you today,
受不了这俩二货先生?
Mr. Can-You-Believe- These-Jack-Asses?
再好不过了...
Just dandy, Mr...
希望我会即兴表演先生
I-Wish-I-Was- Better-At-Improv.
- 再读一个  - 好的好的 呃...
- Read another one.  - Okay, okay. Uh...
"把时空和超冷液
"The analogy between space-time
类比 没有意义或者说...就是胡扯
and a supercooled fluid is either meaningless or... false".
"我希望这个博客能更注重于真正的科学
"I wish this blog would devote itself to real science
而不是在一些又笨
instead of wasting our time with crackpot,
又急于求成的理论家身上"
wannabe theoreticians in a rush to publish".
这是谁写的?
Who wrote that?
匿名发表的
It's anonymous,
用户名是 "广义相对论"
and user name "General Relativity."
嗯... 我要回复他
Well... I'm responding to it.
不要把你自己降低到他的水平
Uh, don't lower yourself to their level.
听着 我只是
Look, I am simply
要为我们的成果辩护 科学家对峙科学家
going to defend our work, scientist to scientist.
说不过他的话
And failing that,
就说他母亲饥不择食
suggest that his mother enjoys a string
人兽通"吃"
of both human and non-human lovers.
Sheldon 我的名字也在论文上
Sheldon, my name's on that paper, too.
这么做没有好处
There's no upside to doing this.
他刚又评论了
He just left another comment.
他怎么说?
What does it say?
"经审查 我改变了主意
"Upon review, I've changed my mind about
"Cooper-Hofstadter假说
"the Cooper-Hofstadter hypothesis
认为时空类似于超液体 事实上
"that space-time is like a superfluid. In fact,
它激励了我创造出我自己的理论
it's inspired me to come up with my own theory.
也许时空就像两个
Maybe space-time is like two clowns
把头塞到木桶里的小丑
with their heads in a bucket,
同Cooper和Hofstadter一样"
much like Cooper and Hofstadter."
我现在能回复了吗?
Can I respond now?
回复吧
Do it.
太岁头上动土 你会尝到厉害的
You mess with the bull, you get the horns.
我要让他看看我家伙有多厉害(猥琐)
I'm about to show this guy just how horny I can be.
还是你们来吧
Somebody else do it.
医生 求你救救我
Doctor, please help me.
我觉得我要变成一只杀人魔猩猩了
I think I might be turning into a killer gorilla.
你为什么觉得自己会变成杀人魔猩猩
Why do you think you're turning into a killer gorilla
而不是正常的猩猩?
and not just a regular gorilla?
因为正常猩猩都是吃素的
Because regular gorillas are vegetarians,
而我刚刚把你接待员的手指咬下来了!
and I just bit the fingers off your receptionist!
- 好了 我们看够了  - 不!
- Okay, we've seen plenty.  - No!
把遥控器给我
Give me the remote.
小心点 她会把你手指咬掉
Careful. She'll bite your fingers off.
好吧 我一直在网上闲逛
Okay, well, I've been poking around the internet,
我觉得我找到了大家更想看的东西
and I think I found something we'll enjoy watching even more.
什么东西?
What is it?
只是一个
Oh, just a video
Bernadette参加选美比赛的视频
of Bernadette in a beauty pageant.
什么?!
What?!
好了 我吸取教训了
Okay, I learned my lesson.
取笑别人是不对的!
Making fun of people is wrong!
我还没吸取教训
I haven't learned my lesson.
快放! 快放!
Play it! Play it!
嗨 我是Bernadette Maryann Rostenkowski
Hi. I'm Bernadette Maryann Rostenkowski
来自加州的约巴林达
from Yorba Linda, California.
你就像一个会讲话的纸杯蛋糕!
You look like a talking cupcake!
你们应该选我
And you should pick me
成为1999届加利福尼亚小姐 因为我想...
for Miss California Quiznos 1999, because I want to...
# 我想我想 我真的真的很想 #
# Tell you what I want, what I really really want #
# I'll tell you what I want, what I really really want#
# 好想好想 好想好想 #
# I wanna, I wanna, I wanna, I wanna#
真的真的很想 成为1999届加利福尼亚小姐
Really, really, really be Miss California Quiznos 1999!
再放一次! 再放一次!
Play it again! Play it again!
他回复了吗?
Did he respond yet?
嗯 还没有
Hmm. No, not yet.
好吧
Well,
也许我们不该堕落到他的水平
maybe we shouldn't have sunk to his level.
也不是很糟
It wasn't that bad.
再读一遍
Read it back one more time.
"这位先生 我们不是傻子 也不是急于求成
"My good sir, we are neither crackpots nor wannabes.
我们是各自领域里的专家
In fact, we are experts in our fields.
你躲在你的匿名之后
And while you hide behind your anonymity,
我们给我们的论文撑腰
we stand behind our paper.
晚上也站你妈身后 给她撑撑腰"
And later tonight, your mother".
你不觉得太过分了吗?
And you don't think that's too rough?
我只是说站在她身后
We're just standing behind her.
又不会大喊一声去吓唬她
It's not like we're gonna say "boo" and scare her.
你怎么可以不告诉我们你参加过选美比赛?
How could you not tell us you were in beauty pageants?
因为很丢人
Cause it's embarrassing.
是挺丢人
It is; it truly is.
好吧...
Yeah, well...
Amy在网上写了关于她自己的
Amy writes Little House on the Prairie fan fiction
"草原上的小木屋"同人小说
about herself and posts it on the Internet.
不是吧!
No!
为什么? 我做什么了?
Why? What did I do?!
抱歉 我得把我身上关注点转移
Sorry, I had to get the spotlight off me,
放到另外一个人的身上 这是选美比赛训练之一
and tearing down other women is part of my pageant training.
好吧 我们现在就去看
Okay. We are reading that right now.
拜托不要
No, please don't.
我们今晚都丢人了 拜托
We got embarrassed tonight. Come on.
但是这很私人的
But it's personal.
为什么? 是关于你和Sheldon的?
Why? Is it about you and Sheldon?
不是
No.
天哪 是关于她和Sheldon的
Oh, my God, it's about her and Sheldon.
不是关于我和Sheldon的
It's not about me and Sheldon.
是关于一个18世纪的叫Amelia的年轻女人...
It's about a young woman in the 1800s named Amelia...
遇到了时光穿越的叫Cooper的物理学家
and the time-traveling physicist named Cooper
并爱上了他
she falls in love with.
- 给我们看看吧?  - 好吗?
- Please show us?  - Please?
- 不  - 我不管怎样都会看到的
- No.  - You know I'm gonna read it either way.
想找到它 没门
Good luck finding it.
Amelia和...
Amelia and...
她的时光穿...
the time-trav...
找到了!
Found it!
"草原上 黎明刚过
"It was just past dawn on the prairie,
如同往日
and like every morning,
Amelia准备做家务
Amelia prepared to do her chores.
可今早却有些不同"
Except something about this morning felt different."
为什么?
Why?
为什么有些不同?
Why did it feel different?
"也许是空气中冬天的气息
"Maybe it was the first whisper of winter in the air,
也许是那个雪白肌肤 奇装异服的
or maybe it was the unconscious handsome man
昏迷着的英俊男子
with porcelain skin and curious clothing
这个她将在草地上找到的男子
she was about to discover lying in the field.
他会走入她的心扉
A man who would open her mind
改写她的命运
to new possibilities
探索她的身体"
and her body to new feelings."
以前 我都是一个人 没有朋友
You know, there was a time when I was alone and had no friends.
我开始怀念那种感觉了
I'm starting to miss that.
他还是没有回复
He still hasn't responded.
他干什么去了?
What's taking him so long?
你这么希望他回复吗?
Do you really want him to write back?
是的 不管他怎么回复
Yeah, I do. No matter how he responds,
我都要狠狠回复一只残念的猫
I am going to destroy him with a picture of a bored cat
说着 "哦 是吗?"
saying, "Oh, really?"
喵噻
Me-wow.
你在干什么?
What are you doing?
我创建了几个新的账号
I've, uh, created some other user accounts
这样就可以给他们的论文刷好评了
so I can post positive comments about their paper.
"这年轻人的理论
"This wee li'l bairn of a theory
甚是让我折服"?
nearly blew my kilt off"?
不 你得用爱丁堡大学的
No. You have to read it how Dr. Angus McDoogal
安格斯 麦克多格教授的口音读出来
of the University of Edinburgh would.
"这年轻淫滴理论
"This wee li'l bairn of a theory
真细让我折服"
nearly blew me kilt off."
他回复了!
He wrote back!
"Cooper和Hofstadter如此幼稚的幽默
"Cooper and Hofstadter resorting to juvenile attempts at humor
恰巧证明他们无法给论文撑腰
is proof they have nothing to back up their ridiculous paper.
这也是情理之中
It should come as no surprise
因为他们在加州理工工作 基本就是技术学校
given they work at Cal Tech, essentially a technical school,
说是物理学家 其实也就是工程师"
where even the physicists are basically engineers."
"工程师"!
"Engineers"!
你知道这有多侮辱人吗?
Do you know how insulting that is?
我知道
Yes.
伙计们 这人只是费尽心思
Guys, this person's just going out of their way
惹你生气罢了
to get a rise out of you.
- 我知道 但是说话也太气人了  - 好吧
- Yeah, but it's still so aggravating.  - Yeah, well,
其他的评论都很正面啊
all the other comments said really nice things.
- 多看看那些  - 对啊
- Focus on those.  - Yeah.
莫斯科大学的
Dr. Dmitri Plancovik
Dmitri Plancovik博士写道
of Moscow University said,
"这论文妙极"
"Dis paper great.
"比起伏特加 我更爱它"
I love it more than 'wodka.".
看 带着口音就对了
See? Better with the accent.
好...
And...
发了
send.
你发了什么?
What did you write?
我受够了受人欺负也只能躲着
I'm done hiding from bullies.
我要跟他在现实社会一较高低
I'm taking this into the real world.
- 什么意思?  - 我跟他说
- What does that mean?  - I told him we'll meet him
我们随时随地恭候他
face-to-face anytime, anywhere.
你疯了吧? 你都不知道这人是谁
Are you crazy? You don't know who this person is.
快删! 快 Sheldon!
Delete that! Come on, Sheldon!
好吧
Oh, okay,
好吧 别激动
okay, calm down.
是他!
It's him!
他视频通话打过来了
He's trying to video chat.
或许我不该把这事带到现实世界里
Perhaps I shouldn't have taken this into the real world.
哦 真的?
Oh, really?
"'时间旅行? 我听不明白'
"'Time travel? I don't understand,'
"Amelia说道 Cooper盯着她说
"said Amelia. Cooper stared at her.
'哪个词你不明白 时间还是旅行?'"
'Which word don't you understand, time or travel?'"
哇 就连在你的幻想中 Sheldon也这么折腾人
Wow, even in your fantasies Sheldon's kind of exhausting.
他一开始是这样
He's like that in the beginning,
好让她以后改变他
so she can change him.
这叫做情节铺垫
It's called good writing.
还有痴人说梦
And wishful thinking.
"当他用这样的语气说她时
"It stung Amelia
"Amelia被打击到了
"when he spoke to her this way.
"在她那只有一间教室的学校里
"In her little one-room schoolhouse,
"她向来是最聪明的学生
"she was always the smartest student,
"常常比过班里的男生们
"regularly besting the boys in her class,
"但现在她面前坐的不是个男孩...
"but this was no boy in front of her...
"而是个男人"
"this was a man."
好戏开始了
Here we go.
"Cooper告诉了Amelia
"Cooper told Amelia
"未来的所有奇妙无比的事物
"about all the strange and incredible things
"比如电脑
"the future would hold, like computers
"还有活过30岁
"and living past 30.
"他问她有没有任何问题
"He asked her if she had any questions.
"而她唯一想问的是
"All she longed to ask was
"他的心跳是否和她一样猛烈
"if his heart was beating as fast as hers,
"但她太害怕了
"but she was too afraid
害怕得不想听到答案"
to hear the answer."
哦 Amelia
Oh, Amelia.
"所以她只是问 在未来
"So instead she asked if, in the future,
Montana是否成了一个州"
Montana ever became a state."
在19世纪 那已经算是调情了
In the 1800s that was considered flirting.
我受够网上的恶意言论了
I'm so sick of people being mean on the Internet.
我觉得匿名发言让每个人觉得
Well, I think the anonymity makes everyone feel like
他们可以放开讲不敢当着人面说的话
they can say things they'd never say to your face.
有意思
Interesting.
我想不到一星半点
I can't think of a single thing
不能当着别人面说的事
I wouldn't say to someone's face.
你这点我倒是一直没发现
Never noticed that about you.
你知道吗? 至少... 你们有所作为
You know what? A... at least you guys did something.
你们... 提出了个理论
You know, you... you had a theory,
你写了篇论文
you wrote a paper,
你们都做出了实际的贡献
you made an actual contribution.
这种家伙只会评判别人的作品
All guys like this do is just stand on other people's work.
他说得对
He's right.
我建议给这个人打回去
I say we call this person back.
我们没必要躲躲藏藏
We've got no reason to hide.
那好 就这么办 打给他
All right, do it. Call him.
让我们看看这个卢瑟有什么成就
Let's find out what this loser's ever accomplished.
跟我一起点
Click it with me.
一 二 三...
One, two, three...
点 点
Click. Click.
你好
Well, hello there.
霍金教授?
Professor Hawking?
兄弟 你该看看自己脸上的表情
Oh, brother, you should see the look on your faces.
你真的不喜欢我们的论文?
You really didn't like our paper?
我很喜欢你们的论文
I like your paper very much.
前提假设很有趣
The premise is intriguing.
那你为什么攻击我们?
Then why are you attacking us?
要是你坐了40年的椅子
If you were sitting in a chair for 40 years,
你也会感到无聊的
you'd get bored, too.
不管怎样
Anyway,
该挂了
got to go.
我答应帮邻居的小孩辅导他的数学作业
I promised to help the neighbor kid with his math homework.
拜拜
Ciao.
史蒂芬・霍金喜欢我们的论文
Stephen Hawking liked our paper.
说前提假设很有趣
Said the premise is intriguing.
很高兴再见到你
Good to see you again,
"霍金喜欢我们的论文"先生
Mr. Stephen-Hawking- Liked-Our-Paper.
你也一样 "我们的前提假设很有趣"先生
And you as well, Mr. Our-Premise-Is-Intriguing.
你最近如何 "我承认这的确很酷"先生?
How do you do, Mr. I'll- Admit-That's-Pretty-Cool?
你总是让我尝受失败的滋味
Yeah, you keep setting me up for failure.
"带着沉重的心情
"With a heavy heart,
"Amelia站在重新修好的时光机面前
"Amelia stood before the newly repaired time machine.
她后悔满足了Cooper的需求"
She regretted giving Cooper the part he needed."
因为她其实想让他满足自己的需求
Because she wanted him to give her the part she needed.
- 好了 说够了  - 什么?
- Okay, that's enough.  - What?
不! 我真得很想知道后来怎么了... Bernadette她也
No! I really want to know what happens... and Bernadette
很想很想知道后来怎么了
really, really, really wants to know what happens.
你们不过是在取笑我
You're just making fun of me.
我只是在开玩笑 对不起
I was just kidding. I'm sorry.
而且故事本身真的很不错!
And the story's really good!
可不是! 他留下来了吗?
No, it is! Does he stay?
他们接吻了吗? 她知道后来Montana怎么了吗?
Do they kiss? Does she find out about Montana?
求求你了?
Please?
好吧
Fine.
"正当Cooper准备离开
"As Cooper prepared to depart,
"Amelia热泪盈眶
"tears filled Amelia's eyes.
"他握紧她的手说 '我不能留下
"He took her hand in his and said, 'I can't stay,
"但我永远不会忘记你的'
"but I will never forget you.'
"他的指尖轻抚着她的脸庞
"He brushed his fingers against her cheek,
"然后飞快地踏进了时光机
"then quickly stepped into the machine.
"请你别走' 她小声说
"'Please don't go,' she whispered.
"但已经太晚了
"But it was too late.
"引擎启动了
"The engine hummed to life.
可他们都没吻上
But they didn't even kiss.
"她转过身
"She turned away,
"擦掉眼泪
"wiping her eyes.
"她不忍这么看着
"She couldn't bear to watch
"她的真爱就此永远消失
"her one chance at true love disappear forever.
"突然... 她感觉有只坚定的手搭在她肩上
"Then... she felt a strong hand on her shoulder
"将她转过身来
"spin her around.
"是Cooper
"It was Cooper.
太好了!
Yes!
"'那未来怎么办?'Amelia问道
"'What about the future?' asked Amelia.
"他深情望着她 低声道
"He looked deeply into her eyes and whispered,
"'没有你 哪有未来'
"'There is no future without you.'
"他把她拉进怀里
"He pulled her in close.
"她开始全身颤抖
"She began to tremble all over.
她能感觉到他那温暖的气息..."
She felt his warm breath..."
你们肯定不信史蒂芬・霍金刚刚说的话
You will not believe what Stephen Hawking just said.
- 出去!  - 等会再说!
- Get out! - Not now!
水够温吗?
Is the water warm enough?
你这么费时费力得烧火
Given the fact that you took the time to build a wood fire,
打来井水并且热好
draw the water from the well and heat it,
要是抱怨就太无礼了
it would be rude to complain.
但既然你问了 水有点凉
But since you asked, it's a little nippy.
我能弄好
I can fix that.
我不禁注意到了你的内衣有些不寻常
I couldn't help but notice your unusual undergarments.
它们不是内衣
They're not undergarments.
它们是超人内裤
They're Underoos.
在我那 它们被认为是
Where I come from, they're known as
"穿起来很酷的内裤"
"underwear that's fun to wear."
那上面的蜘蛛意味着什么?
And what's the significance of the spider?
那代表的是蜘蛛侠
Oh, that represents Spider-Man.
拥有蜘蛛能力令人惊讶
He does whatever a spider can.
未来说话都很讲究押韵 是吗?
There's a lot of rhyming in the future, isn't there?
你说得对
You're right.
这比我想象的还古怪
This is even weirder than I thought.
要我停下来吗?
You want me to stop reading?
你开玩笑吧? 不要停
Are you kidding? No, no.
"当他站起来让Amelia擦干他..."
"As he stood for Amelia to dry him..."
告诉我 Cooper...
So, tell me, Cooper...
未来的做爱方式和现在一样吗?
are the ways of physical love different in the future?
不听了 信息量太大
Yeah, okay, I'm good.